Finding Aid for the Nancy Lee Hall Papers LSC.0273
UCLA Library Special Collections
Nancy Lee Hall papers
1944-1992
1958-1992
UCLA Library Special Collections
Hall, Nancy Lee
LSC.0273
5.5 Linear Feet (9 boxes and 1 carton)
Nancy Lee Hall (1923- ) was born in Rochester, New York. She was a design craftsperson (1964), drama teacher in the San Diego Unified Public Schools (1968) and a social worker at the Alcoholism Counseling and Education Center (1972). She also wrote books, plays and poems. The collection consists of Nancy Hall's manuscripts, correspondence, published materials, notes, research materials, photographs, clippings, cassette tapes, and videotapes.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIO AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audio and audiovisual materials. Audio and audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Nancy Lee Hall, 1992.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9914707223606533
Biography
Hall was born on June 6, 1923 in Rochester, New York; became a design craftsperson for Marine Engineering in 1964; drama teacher, San Diego Unified Public Schools, 1968; social worker, Alcoholism Counseling and Education Center, 1972; wrote A True Story of a Drunken Mother (1974) and True Story of a Single Mother (1982); also wrote plays later produced, including The Freezer, Hut 64, The Room, Babes in Evil, Lost, and What Shall It Profit?
Scope and Content
Collection consists of manuscripts, correspondence, published materials, notes, research materials, photographs, clippings, cassette tapes, and videotapes of writer Nancy Lee Hall. Includes unpublished plays, poems, and articles, as well as manuscripts for A True Story of a Drunken Mother (1974) and True Story of a Single Mother (1982), as well as manuscripts of many plays, later produced.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Unpublished materials (Boxes 1,3).
Published materials (Boxes 2,9).
Notes (Boxes 3-6).
Correspondence (Boxes 6-7).
Biographical (Box 8).
Research materials (Box 9).
Miscellaneous newspapers and magazines (carton).
Women dramatists -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Women authors, American -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Online resources.; Hall, Nancy Lee--Archives.
- Unpublished Material--Plays
  - Mirror Mirror--One act play--Original, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hut 64--One act play--Original and 3 copies (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Freezer--One act play--Original, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - J.D. & Charley--One act play--Original and 2 copies with holograph corrections (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Room--One act play--Original and 3 copies with holograph notes and corrections, and additional leaves of notes (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Babes in Evil--One act play--Original, with play review and program, 1964. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lost--Original and telegram, 1968. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Written critiques--plays. Holograph and typescript notes on loose leaves, 1965-1969. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - What Shall It Profit a Man--Three act play--Original, 3 drafts and holograph notes on loose leaves (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Unpublished Material--Screenplay
  - Then Came Bronson--One photocopy, 1970. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Bosom of Fools--Three act play--Original, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Play: Gabrielle--Two act play. Original, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Play: Housewife Syndrome--Street theatre play. Photocopy, 1970. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Play: Smith!--Original and three programs (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Published Materials
  - Manuscript: True Story of a Drunken Mother--Published in Title to p.147, 1974. 1982. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: True Story of a Drunken Mother--Published in pp.148-191 [end], 1974. 1982. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Manuscript: True Story of a Single Mother (1 of 2)--Published 1984. Drafts, revisions and corrections, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Manuscript: True Story of a Single Mother (2 of 2)--Published in Drafts, revisions and corrections, 1984. 1982. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Manuscript: True Story of a Drunken Mother--Original holograph draft. 216pp., 1958. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Unpublished Materials
  - Manuscript: I am Woman--First draft, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Manuscript: I am Woman--Second draft (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper column - Nancy's Window--Typescript leaves with holograph notes and corrections. Approximately 300+ pp. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Various poems--Typescript, carbon and holograph versions, some with holograph notations. Thirty items, 50 pp., 1958-1989. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Articles and writings--Various titled articles. Approximately 300+ pp. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Notes
  - Affidavit of Daniel P. Sheehan--Photocopy, 1986-1987. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Thelma and Louise--Photocopies of magazine and newspaper articles re the movie, 1991. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Women--Photocopies of political cartoons and newspaper articles, original letters to Nancy Lee Hall re women, abortion, rape, inequality (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Roxanne's case--Newspaper articles, court transcript, correspondence and holograph notes re Roxanne Cornelius vs. San Diego Sheriff Department, (?)., 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Lost, by Nancy Huber--Holograph notes and copies of several Nancy Lee Hall plays including Babes in Evil and Lost, many with holograph notations and corrections (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous (1 of 4)--Holograph notes and typescript pages from several plays (?) and manuscripts, some with holograph notations, 1958-1978. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous (2 of 4)--Holograph notes and typescript pages from several plays (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous (3 of 4)--Holograph notes and copies of several plays (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous (4 of 4)--Holograph notes, correspondence to/from publisher and copies of several plays (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Scapegoats--Holograph notes and photocopy of two letters from a psychiatrist Dr. Bailey to Judge Low re M.A. Maloney, and one open letter re the charges, 1974. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gabrielle--Holograph notes and two copies of play (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks--14 small and 3 large spiral notebooks containing various unidentified holograph notes (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks--11 small spiral notebooks containing various holograph notes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Correspondence
  - From publisher (Daughters, Incorporated) and rejections, 1972-1976. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Letter from Nancy Lee Hall's father--Original and photocopy, 1944. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Letters--personal--Holograph and typescript correspondence, 1973-1990. (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Cards and letters, 1979-1990. (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - Letters--From Keith Rinden, 1967-1968. (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - South End Press--Correspondence and catalogues from South End Press, 1984-1992. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Letters--Letters from publishers, magazines, etc., 1967-1990. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Family--Various flyers, articles [photocopy] and typed biographical history of Milton G. Hall (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Letters from David G. Hall (1st cousin), 1973-1974. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - A woman's letters of protest--Various correspondence to the President, editors, managers, bosses, the Army, etc., many re discrimination, 1970-1988. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Rejections--Rejection letters to Nancy Lee Hall re submissions, 1963-1985. (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Biographical
  - Interview on PBS show, Que Pasa--On videotape [VHS], 1990. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Russian and American women--Interview [1 cassette tape], 1986. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Sue on women--Interview of Sue Rochman [1 cassette tape], 1986. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Martha on women--Interview of Martha McAulliffe [1 cassette tape], 1986. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - First book--Interview with unidentified person(s) [1 cassette tape], 1976. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Nancy Lee Hall--Interview on PBS [1 cassette tape], 1985. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Lillian Kennedy--Two interviews taped in two parts [4 cassette tapes], February and March 1985. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Books that changed my life--Typed list of books for Joan Small, with Holograph otation, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Grossmont College advertisement--Advertisement for Nancy Lee Hall plays (2 copies), 1968. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Book reviews--In San Diego (2 issues) and The New Woman's Survival Sourcebook, 1984-1990. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Book promotion--South End Press catalogue ()., Spring 1990 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - A True Story of a Single Mother--Softcover edition, 1984. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - A True Story of a Drunken Mother--Softcover edition, 1974. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Our Own Movie--Article in The Daily Guardian, 1980. (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Research Materials
  - Classics--16 radical San Diego newspapers, 1968-1980. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Historical album of career--Photos, articles and writings, 1937-1990. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous newspapers and magazines [Carton] (Box 10, Folder 1)